<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Red_Hat_XML_Tag_Usage_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="sect-Documentation-Red_Hat_XML_Tag_Usage_Guide-Commands_Options_and_Arguments">
	<title>Commands, Options, and Arguments</title>
	 <para>
		This chapter describes the recommended DocBook tags to use for commands, options, arguments, and other parameters related primarily to command-line examples and procedures. Exceptions are common, and each case must be evaluated individually. The purpose of this chapter is to provide a starting point for delivering consistent results as often as possible.
	</para>
	 <note>
		<para>
			In all cases, refer to <ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/docbook.html"><citetitle>DocBook: The Definitive Guide</citetitle></ulink> and <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for initial guidance.
		</para>

	</note>
	 <section id="sect-Documentation-Red_Hat_XML_Tag_Usage_Guide-Commands_Options_and_Arguments-Documenting_Commands">
		<title>Documenting Commands</title>
		 <para>
			Commands generally appear in two main scenarios: inline, as part of a general discussion or description of the command; or in a displayed block, as part of an example or procedural step. The second scenario often includes several command options that apply to the specific example or task.
		</para>
		 <para>
			In keeping with the philosophy of "never say never," commands almost always appear inside &lt;command&gt; tags. Even when used in &lt;screen&gt; or similar tags, commands need to be marked up to differentiate them from other text that may appear in a displayed block, for example, computer output. This is especially true because, according to <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide,</citetitle> commands should not be preceded by any sort of command prompt, for example a dollar (&dollar;) or number (#) sign. If they appear as part of body text, commands need to be differentiated from the surrounding text.
		</para>
		 <example id="exam-Documentation-Red_Hat_XML_Tag_Usage_Guide-Documenting_Commands-Marking_up_Commands_in_Body_Text">
			<title>Marking up Commands in Body Text</title>
			 <para>
				Use the &lt;command&gt;ifconfig&lt;/command&gt; command to configure network interfaces.
			</para>
			 <para>
				This is rendered as follows:
			</para>
			 <para>
				Use the <command>ifconfig</command> command to configure network interfaces.
			</para>

		</example>
		 <example id="exam-Documentation-Red_Hat_XML_Tag_Usage_Guide-Documenting_Commands-Marking_up_Commands_in_Examples">
			<title>Marking up Commands in Examples</title>
			 <para>
				Enter the following command to determine the status of the firewall:
			</para>
			 <para>
				&lt;screen&gt;&lt;command&gt;service &lt;option&gt;iptables status&lt;/option&gt;&lt;/command&gt;&lt;/screen&gt;
			</para>
			 <para>
				This is rendered as follows:
			</para>
			 <para>
				Enter the following command to determine the status of the firewall: 
<screen><command>service <option>iptables status</option></command></screen>

			</para>

		</example>

	</section>
	

</section>


