<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines">
	<title>General Tag Usage Guidelines</title>
	 <para>
		This is the egg of the book, and for now everything is in one chapter. That is bound to change, but we have to start somewhere. The place to really start is <ulink url="www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/docbook.html" /> Another useful discussion site is <ulink url="http://www.dpawson.co.uk/docbook/markup.html" /> although it is somewhat dated, and not all of the link targets are accessible.
	</para>
	 <section id="sect-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines-Abbreviations_Acronyms_and_Initialisms">
		<title>Abbreviations, Acronyms, and Initialisms</title>
		 <para>
			The Red&nbsp;Hat Cloud documentation team has adopted the following practice for marking up abbreviations, acronyms, and initialisms.
		</para>
		 <para>
			<citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> provides guidelines for DITA tags for highlighting (see p. 276). This is not intended or expected to be a comprehensive guide for how to tag various elements, but lacking any better reference, the Cloud documentation team has adopted the recommendation to not tag abbreviations, acronyms, and initialisms.
		</para>
		 <note>
			<para>
				For a discussion about how to use abbreviations, acronyms, and initialisms correctly, see <citetitle>The Red&nbsp;Hat Writing&nbsp;Style&nbsp;Guide</citetitle> at <ulink url="https://url.corp.redhat.com/RHStyleGuide" />
			</para>

		</note>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines-API_Calls">
		<title>API Calls</title>
		 <para>
			Only minimal discussion has occurred with respect to tagging API calls. The results so far are as follows: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The Middleware Business Unit uses &lt;code&gt; tags for simplicity's sake, despite their inaccuracy. In a generic sense this is probably fine.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						In more specific cases you need to identify &lt;method&gt;, &lt;function&gt;, and related terms.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</para>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines-Applications">
		<title>Applications</title>
		 <para>
			One of the problem areas here is identifying when something is actually an application, a command, a service, or perhaps an "alias"; for example, tools, utilities, and other terms are often used, but there is no clear definition of what these are when it comes to applying DocBook tags.
		</para>
		 <para>
			The following entries have been entered and discussed:
		</para>
		 <variablelist id="vari-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Applications-Applications_Packages_and_Daemons">
			<title>Applications, Packages, and Daemons</title>
			 <varlistentry id="varl-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Applications_Packages_and_Daemons-PostgreSQL">
				<term>PostgreSQL</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						PostgreSQL server and RHEV-M server: In these cases, "PostgreSQL" and "RHEV-M" are both applications and should be tagged as such.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry id="varl-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Applications_Packages_and_Daemons-postgresql">
				<term>postgresql</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						postgresql<superscript>1</superscript>: Refers to the package that you install on the computer. In this case, tag it with a &lt;package&gt; tag.
					</para>
					 <para>
						postgresql<superscript>2</superscript>: Refers to the daemon (or service) that the package provides. In this case, tag it with a &lt;systemitem class="daemon"&gt; tag.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>

	</section>
	
	 <xi:include href="Commands_Options_Arguments.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	 <section id="sect-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines-Punctuation">
		<title>Punctuation</title>
		 <para>
			This section describes the preferred methods for tagging punctuation marks should that prove necessary. Ordinarily this is not required, but in some cases, for example ellipses and greater than and less than symbols, using DocBook tags or entities may be required to ensure the integrity of the XML file.
		</para>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Refer to the appropriate sections of <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> and other standard references for general punctuation guidelines.
			</para>

		</note>
		 <variablelist>
			<varlistentry id="varl-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Punctuation-Quotation_Marks_and_quote_Tags">
				<term>Quotation Marks and &lt;quote&gt; Tags</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						To quote <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide:</citetitle> <blockquote>
							<attribution><citetitle>The IBM Style Guide, Chapter 2. Punctuation</citetitle></attribution> <para>
								The term quotation mark refers generically to a double quotation mark character or a single quotation mark character.
							</para>

						</blockquote>

					</para>
					 <para>
						The decision not to use &lt;quote&gt; tags whenever double quotation marks are required in Red&nbsp;Hat documentation was reached after a lengthy discussion involving both writers and translators. No significant justification for their use was provided, and several good reasons not to use them were offered.
					</para>
					 <para>
						As a result of this discussion, the current recommendation is to use the standard quotation mark key on your keyboard whenever single or double quotation marks are required in Red&nbsp;Hat documentation.
					</para>
					 <note>
						<para>
							Not all languages use the same characters where English uses double quotation marks. The localization team has their own style guides for treating such characters.
						</para>

					</note>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines-User_Interface_Objects">
		<title>User Interface Objects</title>
		 <para>
			This section describes the preferred methods for tagging various user interface objects.
		</para>
		 <variablelist id="vari-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-User_Interface_Objects-Menus_Submenus_and_Menu_Items">
			<title>Menus, Submenus, and Menu Items</title>
			 <varlistentry id="varl-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Menus_Submenus_and_Menu_Items-GUI_Menus">
				<term>GUI Menus</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Use the following syntax and tags when documenting GUI menus, submenus, and menu items. Note that there are no spaces or other punctuation between tags or elements. See <xref linkend="exam-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-GUI_Menus-Example_Output_Using_Prescribed_GUI_Tags" /> for example output.
					</para>
					 <para>
						&lt;menuchoice&gt;&lt;guimenu&gt;System&lt;/guimenu&gt;&lt;guisubmenu&gt;Preferences&lt;/guisubmenu&gt;&lt;guimenuitem&gt;Mouse&lt;/guimenuitem&gt;&lt;/menuchoice&gt;
					</para>
					 <example id="exam-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-GUI_Menus-Example_Output_Using_Prescribed_GUI_Tags">
						<title>Example Output Using Prescribed GUI Tags</title>
						 <para>
							<menuchoice><guimenu>System</guimenu><guisubmenu>Preferences</guisubmenu><guimenuitem>Mouse</guimenuitem></menuchoice>
						</para>

					</example>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-General_Tag_Usage_Guidelines-Questionable_Tags_or_Tags_to_Avoid">
		<title>Questionable Tags, or Tags to Avoid</title>
		 <para>
			This section is currently designed to list tags that have been used incorrectly, or that provide no real benefit. Mostly all they do is increase maintenance and overhead.
		</para>
		 <variablelist>
			<varlistentry id="varl-product-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Questionable_Tags_or_Tags_to_Avoid-markup">
				<term>markup</term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						See <ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/markup.html"><citetitle>The DocBook Guide</citetitle></ulink> for a definition and description of how to use this tag.
					</para>
					 <para>
						This tag has been used in some cases to mark up various elements related to methods and their attributes. For this use case, you should investigate the method* tags.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>

	</section>
	

</chapter>

