<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="sect-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters">
	<title>Variables, Options, and Parameters</title>
	 <para>
		How often have you been confused about whether to tag something as a variable, as an option, as optional, or even as a literal? Happens to me all the time. Hopefully this will help. I need help too; I admit it. Feel free to volunteer thoughts.
	</para>
	 <para>
		It might be a good idea to start with a few definitions, or at least what will serve as definitions.
	</para>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="varl-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters-Variable">
			<term>Variable</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A symbolic name associated with a value and whose associated value may be changed (from <ulink url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variable">Wikipedia</ulink>. DocBook supports several tags that you can use for variables; I'll introduce them as needed.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters-Option">
			<term>Option</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					An option for a software command (from <ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/option.html" />). This definition sounds somewhat restrictive, because options can apply to more than just software commands. Ultimately, however, I think all options find their way to a command, so let's leave it at that for now.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters-Optional">
			<term>Optional</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The Optional element indicates that a specified argument, option, or other text is optional. The precise meaning of "optional" varies according to the application or process begin documented. (From <ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/optional.html" />) Note the difference between this and &lt;option&gt;.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters-Parameter">
			<term>Parameter</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					This can be a bit of a pain. What it is depends on who you ask: 
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								In computing a parameter is defined as "a reference or value that is passed to a function, procedure, subroutine, command, or program" (from <ulink url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parameter#Computing" /> which actually gets it from <ulink url="http://www.thefreedictionary.com/parameter" />)
							</para>

						</listitem>
						 <listitem>
							<para>
								<ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/parameter.html" /> declares a parameter to be "A value or a symbolic reference to a value". It states that "A parameter identifies something passed from one part of a computer system to another."
							</para>
						</listitem>

					</itemizedlist>

				</para>
				 <para>
					As you can see, it's a bit painful. I try to avoid it.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters-Literal">
			<term>Literal</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<ulink url="http://www.docbook.org/tdg/en/html/literal.html" /> has its own description of this tag, and it's not something that we use a lot. Actually we use it a lot more than we should, and usually incorrectly. I'm going to ignore it for now, except perhaps to offer examples of when NOT to use it.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
	 <section id="sect-Tips_for_Writers-DocBook_Tag_Usage_Guide-Variables_Options_and_Parameters-Examples">
		<title>Examples</title>
		 <para>
			Descriptions and definitions are all well and good, but sometimes a few sound examples go a long way.
		</para>
		 <remark>Do this part soon</remark>

	</section>

</section>

